Register of the Spartacist League of the U.S. records
Hoover Institution Archives
Spartacist League of the U.S. records
1964-2016
94062
Hoover Institution Archives
24 manuscript boxes (10.0 linear feet)
Records of the American Trotskyist political organization include minutes, internal bulletins, pamphlets, position papers, press releases, flyers, and leaflets relating to Trotskyist political activities in the United States. Includes issuances of youth groups and international affiliates of the Spartacist League.
Spartacist League of the U.S.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1994, with increments received in subsequent years, through 2017.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Spartacist League of the U.S. is a self-proclaimed revolutionary communist organization in the Marxist-Leninist-Trotskyist tradition. Its antecedents date to the early 1960s and stem from the Revolutionary Tendency within the Socialist Workers Party, American sympathizing section of the Fourth International (International Committee) at that time. The Revolutionary Tendency espoused a number of criticisms of the majority leadership of the Socialist Workers Party, notably its decision to participate in the reunified Fourth International (United Secretariat) and its uncritically favorable assessment of the Fidel Castro regime in Cuba. These differences eventuated in expulsion of leaders of the Revolutionary Tendency at the end of 1963 and their formation of a group around the publication Spartacist early in 1964. Following failure to achieve agreement with remaining elements of the Fourth International (International Committee), the group formally founded the Spartacist League of the U.S. in 1966.
International activities of the Spartacist League resulted in formation of an international Spartacist tendency following a European conference in 1974. This international tendency, including sections in Australia and New Zealand, Canada, and several European countries, transformed itself into the International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist) in 1989.
Domestically, a youth affiliate of the Spartacist League appeared initially as the Revolutionary Marxist Caucus within Students for a Democratic Society in 1969. This was succeeded in turn by Revolutionary Communist Youth (1971-1974), the Spartacus Youth League (1974-1986), and, after a hiatus, reconstituted Spartacus Youth Clubs.
Two other domestic affiliates are the Partisan Defense Committee, established to provide aid to leftist and labor prisoners, and the Prometheus Research Library, a facility for documentation of the history of the Trotskyist movement.
In addition to its theoretical journal Spartacist, the principal publications of the Spartacist League press have been its newspaper Workers Vanguard, its youth newspaper Young Spartacus, and its Women’s Commission journal Women and Revolution.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Spartacist League records in the Hoover Institution Archives include internally circulated materials from the inception of the organization up through 2004, and ephemeral publications and other public issuances up through 2016. Serial runs and other substantial publications of the Spartacist press can be found in the Hoover Institution Library. All materials held are open for use.
The records are arranged in six series. The Spartacist League Internal Issuances series is limited to internal issuances of the League itself. In addition to minutes of meetings of its leading bodies and internal bulletins, it includes a chronologically arranged file of internally circulated letters and other documents.
The Spartacist League Public Issuances series includes pamphlets, election campaign literature, and a few short-lived serial runs. It also includes a number of public bulletins of a documentary historical nature, amicus curiae briefs filed by the League in cases which it considered to involve significant legal issues, and a chronologically arranged file of leaflets and flyers.
Two other series, Partisan Defense Committee Issuances and Prometheus Research Library Issuances, contain public issuances of those two affiliates of the League.
A series of Youth Affiliate Issuances contains both internal and public issuances of the League’s successive youth affiliates up through liquidation of the Spartacus Youth League in 1986. These include minutes, internal bulletins, public bulletins, and some other ephemeral public issuances. Pamphlets published under youth affiliate imprints, however, are interfiled with adult group pamphlets in the Spartacist League Public Issuances series. The International Affiliate Issuances series includes internal issuances of the international Spartacist tendency--minutes, internal bulletins, and a chronologically arranged file of internally circulated material. It also includes non-English language pamphlets and short serial runs published by the Spartacist League, and a few pamphlets issued by European sections of the international Spartacist tendency and International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist).
Socialism--United States.; Communism--United States.; Fourth International.
- Spartacist League Internal Issuances, 1964-2004 (Boxes 1-6, 14-16, 23-24)
  Scope and Contents note
  Internal issuances of the Spartacist League, including minutes, internal bulletins, and circulated material.
  - Minutes, 1964-2002
    Includes attachments to minutes and some agendas.
    - New York Local Committee
      - 1964 November 4, 18, December 2, 16 (Box-folder 1: 1)
      - 1965 January 6, 20, February 3, 17, March 3, 17, 31, April 14, 21, May 5, 19, June 2, 16, 30, July 21, August 4, 18, 25, September 9, 23, October 7, 21, November 4, 11, 18, December 2, 16, 30 (Box-folder 1: 2)
      - 1966 January 13, 27, February 10, 24, March 10, 24, April 7, 14, 17, 28, May 12, 26 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Resident Editorial Board
      - 1965 April 12, 26, May 8, 24, June 14, 28, July 12, August 2, 23, September 13, October 4, 26, November 15, December 6, 20, 27 (Box-folder 1: 4)
      - 1966 January 10, 24, February 28, March 14, April 25, May 2, 16, 23, 30, June 20, 27, July 4, 18, 25, August 8, 22, 29, September 2 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Political Bureau
      - 1966 September 19, 26, October 3, 10, 17, 31, November 14, December 5, 26 (Box-folder 1: 6)
      - 1967 January 2, 23, February 13, 27, March 27, April 10, May 8, 21, June 12, July 10, 31, August 21, September 11, 25, October 2, 8, 24, November 7, 14 (Box-folder 1: 7)
      - 1968 January 23, 30, February 19, March 25, April 1, 22, May 6, 20, June 3, 10, July 1, 8, 29, August 22, September 16, November 4, 18, December 16 (Box-folder 1: 8)
      - 1969 January 20, February 12, 24, March 17, 24, April 9, May 12, June 9, 30, August 4, December 31 (Box-folder 1: 9)
      - 1970 April 28, May 18, June 15, 25, July 27, August 10, 24, September 9, 23, December 12, 21 (Box-folder 1: 10)
      - 1971 January 10, February 15, March 29, April 6, 28, June 19, December 13, 23 (Box-folder 1: 11)
      - 1972 January 9, March 10, May 15, 20, June 24, July 15, August 24, September 11, 18, November 5, December 16-17 (Box-folder 1: 12)
      - 1973 March 11, July 23, September 3, October 21, 29, November 1, December 4, 11 (Box-folder 1: 13)
      - 1974 January 7, February 18, March 12, 22, April 15, May 13, 22-23, June 12, July 17, 24, 31, September 17, November 7, 26 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - 1975 October 29 (Box-folder 2: 2)
      - 1976 January 28, July 14, December 9 (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - 1977 February 10, July 20 (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - 1978 July 21 (Box-folder 2: 5)
      - 1979 October 25, November 7 (Box-folder 2: 6)
      - 1980 March 2, 23, April 6, August 12, 31, December 6 (Box-folder 2: 7)
      - 1981 April 7, May 6, September 23, November 12 (Box-folder 2: 8)
      - 1982 January 22, February 28, March 24-25, July 27, November 29 (Box-folder 2: 9)
      - 1983 January 13, July 19, September 24 (Box-folder 2: 10)
      - 1984 March 5, May 29, October 25 (Box-folder 2: 11)
      - 1985 February 23, June 1, July 26, November 10 (Box-folder 2: 12)
      - 1986 February 6, June 10, November 2 (Box-folder 2: 13)
      - 1987 March 11, May 7, June 16, November 22 (Box-folder 2: 14)
      - 1988 June 8, October 9, November 9, December 15 (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - 1989 June 11, October 2, 20 (Box-folder 14: 2)
      - 1990 September 13 (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - 1991 January 15 (Box-folder 14: 4)
      - 1992 June 30, September 22, October 17, November 27 (Box-folder 14: 5)
      - 1993 February 4, 27, March 30, April 11, June 3, September 2-3, 23, 29, October 23, November 16, December 2, 29 (Box-folder 14: 6)
      - 1994 January 26, March 31, May 4, June 9, July 27, September 2, October 7, November 12, December 29 (Box-folder 14: 7)
      - 1995 February 14, March 28, May 9, June 8, 29, August 24, 31, September 28, October 23, December 11 (Box-folder 14: 8)
      - 1996 January 9, March 14, April 11, 18, May 28, June 8, 27, July 9, August 12, 31, September 12, 28, November 2, 9, 10, 15, December 4 (Box-folder 14: 9)
      - 1997 January 8, February 8, March 12, May 15, June 28, July 10, 21, August 21, September 18, October 8, 21 (Box-folder 14: 10)
      - 1998 January 6, March 5, April 9, May 27, July 2, 15, August 29, September 11, 29, October 28, November, 2, 17, 24, December 10 (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - 1999 January 14, 21, February 21, March 4, 24, April 12, 19, 27, May 7, 21, June 2, 18, July 9, 12, 13, 20, August 9, September 17, October 13, 15, 24, 29, November 4, 13, 19, 30, December 12, 14, 22 (Box-folder 23: 2)
      - 2000 January 6, February 1, 10, March 9, April 4, 13, May 4, 13, June 1, July 13, August 16, September 10, 16, October 5, November 11, 18, December 14, 26 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      - 2001 January 10, 12, 15, February 10, 21, April 4, May 9, June 7, July 3, August 8, 16, September 7, 12, 15, 18, October 1, 17, 23, 29, November 14, 20, December 18, 19 (Box-folder 23: 4)
      - 2002 January 10, 24, February 25, March 21, April 4, May 2, June 6 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Central Committee
      - 1967 December 30-31 (Box-folder 2: 15)
      - 1969 September 1 (Box-folder 2: 16)
      - 1970 September 5-7 (Box-folder 2: 17)
      - 1971 September 5-6 (Box-folder 2: 18)
      - 1973 August 15 (Box-folder 2: 19)
      - 1974 March 16-17, August 27, 31 (Box-folder 2: 20)
      - 1975 August 15 (Box-folder 2: 21)
      - 1977 June 22, 25 (Box-folder 2: 22)
      - 1979 July 21-22 (Box-folder 2: 23)
      - 1980 August 22 (Box-folder 2: 24)
      - 1981 November 27-28 (Box-folder 2: 25)
      - 1982 July 17 (Box-folder 2: 26)
      - 1983 March 26-27, December 17-18 (Box-folder 2: 27)
      - 1985 July 27-29 (Box-folder 2: 28)
      - 1986 October 5 (Box-folder 2: 29)
      - 1987 September 17, 20 (Box-folder 2: 30)
      - 1990 October 6-7 (Box-folder 14: 11)
      - 1991 June 8, October 26-27 (Box-folder 14: 12)
      - 1993 April 24-25 (Box-folder 14: 13)
      - 1994 February 19-20, June 23, 27 (Box-folder 14: 14)
      - 1996 November 9-10 (Box-folder 14: 15)
      - 1997 March 23, November 2 (Box-folder 14: 16)
      - 1998 April 26, November 7-8 (Box-folder 23: 6)
      - 1999 March 20-21, June 21, 26 (Box-folder 23: 7)
      - 2000 January 15-16, June 17-18, October 21-22 (Box-folder 23: 8)
      - 2001 December 8-9 (Box-folder 23: 9)
      - 2002 June 19 (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - National Conferences
      - 2nd, 1969 August 30-September 1 (Box-folder 2: 31)
      - 3rd, 1972 November 24-26 (Box-folder 2: 32)
      - 5th, 1977 June 23-25 (Box-folder 2: 33)
      - 6th, 1980 August 21-24 (Box-folder 2: 34)
    - Trade Union Commission
      - 1973 December 16, 30 (Box-folder 14: 17)
      - 1974 January 20, 27, February 9, March 10, 29, April 14, 28, May 19, June 18, July 15, August 2, October 22, November 3 (Box-folder 14: 18)
      - 1975 January 31, March 16, May 8, 30, July 2, August 5, November 9 (Box-folder 14: 19)
      - 1976 January 16 (Box-folder 14: 20)
      - 1993 March 6 (Box-folder 14: 21)
      - 1996 December 18 (Box-folder 14: 22)
      - 1997 April 2, October 16 (Box-folder 14: 23)
    - Women's Commission
      - 1974 February 19, March 28, April 16, 30, June 25, August 4, September 28, November 1, December 20 (Box-folder 14: 24)
      - 1975 February 28, June 2, December 18 (Box-folder 14: 25)
      - 1976 March 22 (Box-folder 14: 26)
    - Black Work Consultative Fraction
      - 1974 September 18, December 6 (Box-folder 14: 27)
      - 1975 March 20, April 28, August 6, 13, September 9 (Box-folder 14: 28)
      - 1976 February 9 (Box-folder 14: 29)
  - Internal chronological file, 1964-2002
    Circular letters, memoranda, reports, position papers, statements, declarations, and resolutions.
    - 1964 (Box-folder 2: 35)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 2: 36)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 2: 37)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 2: 38)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 2: 39)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 2: 40)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 2: 41)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 2: 42)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 2: 43)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 2: 44)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 2: 45)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 2: 46)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 2: 47)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 2: 48)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 2: 49)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 2: 50)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 2: 51)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 2: 52)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 23: 13)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 23: 14)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 23: 15)
  - Internal bulletins, 1964-2004
    Title varies: Pre-Conference Discussion Material, Internal Information Bulletin, Pre-Conference Discussion Bulletin, Internal Bulletin, Internal Information Bulletin, Internal Discussion Bulletin, Discussion Bulletin, Internal Information and Discussion Bulletin.
    - No. 1 [originally unnumbered], 1964 November (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - No. 2 [originally unnumbered], 1965 June (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - No. 3, 1965 July (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - No. 4, 1966 July (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - No. 5, 1966 August (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - No. 6, 1966 September (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - No. 7, 1968 December (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - No. 8, 1969 July (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - No. 9, 1969 July (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - No. 10, 1969 August (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - No. 11, 1970 April (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - No. 12, 1970 April (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - No. 13, 1970 April (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - No. 14, 1972 June (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - No. 15, 1972 August (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - No. 16, 1972 September (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - No. 17, 1972 October (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - No. 18, 1972 November (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - No. 19, 1972 November (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - No. 20, 1972 November (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - No. 21, 1974 June (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - No. 22, 1974 August (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - No. 23, 1974 August (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - No. 24, 1974 August (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - No. 25, 1975 April (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - No. 26, 1975 August (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - No. 27, 1977 June (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - No. 28, 1977 June (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - No. 29, 1977 June (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - No. 30, 1978 June (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - No. 31, 1980 July (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - No. 32, 1980 August (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - No. 33, 1980 August (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - No. 34, 1981 May (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - No. 35, 1981 November (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - No. 36, 1981 November (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - No. 37, 1982 August (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - No. 38, 1983 July (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - No. 39, 1983 August (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - No. 40, 1983 August (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - No. 41, 1983 August (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - No. 42, 1983 August (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - No. 43, 1984 March (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - No. 44, 1985 July (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - No. 45, 1985 November (Box-folder 5: 14)
    - No. 46, 1986 March (Box-folder 5: 15)
    - No. 47, 1987 June (Box-folder 5: 16)
    - No. 48, 1987 September (Box-folder 5: 17)
    - No. 49, 1988 January (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - No. 50, 1990 June (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - No. 51, 1991 September (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - No. 52, 1992 July (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - No. 53, 1993 March (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - No. 54, 1993 April (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - No. 55, 1993 October (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - No. 56, 1994 April (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - No. 57, 1994 June (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - No. 58, 1994 June (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - No. 59, 1996 September (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - No. 60, 1996 October (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - No. 61, 1996 December (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - No. 62, 1997 October (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - No. 63, 1999 April (Box-folder 23: 16)
    - No. 64, 1999 May (Box-folder 23: 17)
    - No. 65, 1999 June (Box-folder 23: 18)
    - No. 66, 1999 June (Box-folder 23: 19)
    - No. 67, 2000 June (Box-folder 23: 20)
    - No. 68, 2000 September (Box-folder 23: 21)
    - No. 69, 2000 September (Box-folder 23: 22)
    - No. 70, 2000 October (Box-folder 23: 23)
    - No. 71, 2001 May (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - No. 72, 2002 March (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - No. 73, 2002 April (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - No. 74, 2002 April (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - No. 75, 2002 May (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - No. 76, 2002 June (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - No. 77, 2004 March (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Marxist Studies bulletin, 1969-1990
    Reprints of documents for member education.
    - No. 1, 1969 March (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - No. 2/3, 1969 July (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - No. 4, 1969 December (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - No. 5, 1973 July (Box-folder 5: 22)
    - No. 6, 1970 August (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - No. 7, 1970 December (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - No. 8, 1990 February (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Internal trade union bulletins, 1973-1976
    Title varies: Internal Trade Union Information Bulletin, Trade Union Commission Discussion Bulletin.
    - No. 1, 1973 July (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Unnumbered, 1976 October (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - No. 2, 1976 November (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - No. 3, 1976 November (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - No. 4, 1976 December (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - No. 5, 1976 December (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Duplicates (Box-folder 16: 7-11)
  - Party Builder, 1975-1986
    - No. 1, 1975 August (Box-folder 16: 12)
    - No. 2, 1977 June (Box-folder 16: 13)
    - No. 3, 1978 September (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - No. 4, 1986 June (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - New York Local Internal Discussion Bulletin, no. 1, 1987 January (Box-folder 16: 16)
- Spartacist League Public Issuances, 1964-2016 (Boxes 6-9, 17, 21, 24)
  Public issuances of the Spartacist League, including public bulletins, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, statements, declarations, press releases, regional serial issues, election campaign literature, and amicus curiae briefs.
  - Marxist Bulletin, 1964-1991
    Documentary reprintings of originally internal issuances.
    - No. 1, In Defense of a Revolutionary Perspective: A Statement of Basic Position by the Revolutionary Tendency, Presented to the June 1962 Plenary Meeting of the SWP National Committee, 1965 January (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - No. 2, The Nature of the Socialist Workers Party--Revolutionary or Centrist? Discussion Material of the Revolutionary Tendency within the SWP, 1965 September (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - No. 3, Part I, The Split in the Revolutionary Tendency: Documents and Correspondence on the 1962 Rupture by Philips, Wohlforth and Healy of the Minority Tendency of the SWP, 1968 April (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - No. 3, Part II, Wohlforth against the R. T., 1970 August (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - No. 3, Part IV, Conversations with Wohlforth: Minutes of the Spartacist-ACFI Unity Negotiating Sessions, 1970 April (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - No. 4, Part I, Expulsion from the Socialist Workers Party: Documents on the Exclusion of Revolutionary Tendency Supporters, 1967 October (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - No. 4, Part II, Expulsion from the Socialist Workers Party: Documents on the Exclusion of Revolutionary Tendency Supporters, 1967 October (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - No. 5, What Strategy for Black Liberation? Trotskyism vs. Black Nationalism: Key Documents and Articles, 1955-1978, 1964 June; revised edition 1978 September (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - No. 7, The Leninist Position on Youth-Party Relations: Documents from the YSA and SWP, 1957-61, 1967 September (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - No. 8, Cuba and Marxist Theory: Selected Documents on the Cuban Question, 1966 June (Box-folder 6: 16)
    - No. 9, Basic Documents of the Spartacist League, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - No. 9, Supplement, Organizational Rules and Guidelines, 1991 March (Box-folder 6: 18)
    - No. 10, "From Maoism to Trotskyism": Documents on the Development of the Communist Working Collective of Los Angeles, 1971 October (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Hate Trotskyism, Hate the Spartacist League bulletin, 1975-1999
    Reprinting documents by rival organizations critical of the Spartacist League.
    - No. 1, 1975 March (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - No. 2, 1975 April (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - No. 3, 1975 August (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - No. 4, 1986 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - No. 5, 1988 July (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - No. 6, 1991 March (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - No. 7, 1992 October (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - No. 8, 1993 July (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - No. 9, 1996 August (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - No. 10, 1997 January (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - No. 11, 1997 October (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - No. 12, 1999 December (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Black History and the Class Struggle pamphlet, 1983-2016
    - No. 1 [originally unnumbered], 1983 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - No. 2, 1985 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - No. 3, 1986 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - No. 4, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - No. 5, 1988 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - No. 6, 1989 (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - No. 7, 1990 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - No. 8, 1991 (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - No. 9, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    - No. 10, 1993 (Box-folder 7: 20)
    - No. 11, 1994 (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - No. 12, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 22)
    - No. 13, 1996 (Box-folder 7: 23)
    - No. 14, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 24)
    - No. 15, 1998 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - No. 16, 2001 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - No. 17, 2003 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - No. 18, 2005 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - No. 19, 2006 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - No. 20, 2007 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - No. 21, 2011 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - No. 22, 2012 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - No. 23, 2013 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - No. 24, 2014 (Box-folder 24: 8)
    - No. 25, 2016 (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Spartacist East (New York City regional publication), no. 1 (April), no. 2 (June), no. 3 (October), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Spartacist South (Southern regional publication), Vol. 1, no. 1, 1968 February-March (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Spartacist West (Bay Area regional publication), 1966-1970 (Box-folder 7: 27)